Hi, I'm Andrew Pastor,
大家好 我是 Andrew Pastor
and I'm a Content Developer for the Intro to Self-Driving Car Nanodegree.
我是无人驾驶纳米学位课程的内容开发人员
So I wanted to do a walkthrough of the C++ optimization project.
以前就想做一个关于 C++ 优化项目的入门课程
So, in this project,
在这个纳米学位项目中
you're given a histogram filter code in C++ that already works.
你将得到一个 C++ 直方图过滤器代码 而且它已经工作了
So you can run it.
所以你可以运行它
It runs correctly, and everything's fine.
它运行正常 一切都很好
The issue with the code is that it has a lot of inefficiencies.
但这个代码有很多效率低下的问题
So, everything that you've been learning in this optimization lesson,
所以 你在这个优化课程中学到的一切
you can apply to this code and get it to run faster.
都可以应用到此代码 目的是使其运行得更快
And one of the fun parts about this project is that a lot of students are going
关于这个项目的一个有趣的部分是 很多学生将要去 Slack 上
on the Slack and competing with each other
并且会在上面相互竞争
just to show how fast they're able to make their code.
比一比他们完成编码的速度有多快
So, if you're up for the challenge,
所以 如果你要做好这次挑战的准备
after you're finished, go on Slack and post your results in the C++ channel.
完成后 去 Slack 上并将你的结果发布到 C++ 板块中
I also want to mention that this project is non-graded.
另外我再提一下 这个项目是不评分的
So it's up to you to do the project and get to the point that you want to.
所以做不做这个项目并达到你想要的程度 这都取决于你
There's a solution that's been provided at the end that
最后 我们会提供了一个参考答案
you can compare your results with but again, it's non-graded.
你可以把你的结果与之作比较 但是需要提醒的是 它也是不评分的
So, let's just walk through the project and see what we've got here.
所以 让我们来看看这个项目 看看我们在这里要学习什么
When you open the project,
当你打开该项目时
you're going to go to this overview page,
你将看到这个概述页面
which I suggest you read through.
我建议你首先阅读一遍这个页面的内容
I'm going to talk about some of the stuff today anyway,
总之 我今天要讲的是这些方面的东西
but it gives an overview of what the project is about.
这个页面都给出了相关的概况
Then, when you click here on project code,
之后 当你点击这里的项目代码时
it's going to open this embedded terminals workspace for you,
它将为你打开这个嵌入式终端工作区
and there is this instructions file already here.
说明文件已经在这里了
So what have we provided for you exactly?
那么 我们具体为你准备了什么呢？
So, over here, we have this folder that says, "Andy_histogram_filter."
在这里 有一个这样的文件夹 上面写着 “ Andy_histogram_filter ”
And then, we have this folder, optimized_code.
之后 还有一个 optimize_code 这样的文件夹
So, both of these folders actually contain the exact same C++ code.
这两个文件夹的 C++ 代码 实际上完全相同
If you open them up, double-click on them,
如果你打开并双击它们
here are all the files.
就会显示出所有的文件
Let's go back, open the optimized_code folder,
让我们回去 打开 optimize_code 文件夹
has the same exact code.
这个文件夹的代码和那个完全相同
The reason why we've provided it twice for you is
我们为你提供两次代码的原因是
because that way, in andy_histogram_filter,
因为 这样的话 在 andy_histogram_filter 中
you have all of the original code and then you can
你拥有了所有的原始代码 然后就可以
put your optimized code and your changes into this optimized_code folder.
将你优化过的代码和更改版本放到这个 optimized_code 文件夹中
So that way, you always have a copy of the original code and you
这样 你会始终拥有原始代码的副本
have a copy of whatever changes you've made so that you can go back and compare them.
你做的任何更改 都会有一个副本 以便你可以回去对它们进行比较
We've also provided this text file called hints.md.
我们还提供了这个名为 hints.md 的文本文件
I'm not going to open it because it's only
我将不会打开它 原因如下
provided if you feel like you're getting stuck and
如果你觉得自己遇到困难了
you're not sure what to do and what to optimize,
不知道该做什么 不知道该优化什么 这时这个文件才会派上用场
but it provides extra hints for how to go about the project and
它会给你额外的提示 告诉你如何执行该项目
how to think about what can be optimized in each of the files.
如何思考在每个文件中可以优化的内容
So, let's just go,
现在 我们开始吧
and we're going to open andy_histogram_filter first.
首先打开 andy_histogram_filter 文件夹
So, if I open main,
然后再打开 main 文件夹
what do we see here?
我们在这里看到什么呢？
So, all of these include statements of these headers.
看到的内容是这些标头的陈述
This is the meat of it.
这是它的“内容”
So here we have iterations 10,000.
然后 我们在这里迭代 10,000 次
What this is saying is that each function is going to be run 10,000 times.
意思是说 每个函数将运行 10,000 次
And we go down here.
我们接着往下看
We're making this vector,
我们正在制作这个矢量
which represents a robot grid which you should be familiar with.
这个矢量代表你应该熟悉的机器人网格
And we've said here.
我们在这里说过
It's red, green, red, red, red, green, red, red, green, green, et cetera.
它是 r、g、r、r、r g、r、r、g、g 等
Now, what does this code do?
这段代码是用来干什么的呢？
We have this clock that starts over again,
这里有一个重新开始的时钟
goes through 10,000 iterations,
它会重复 10,000 次
going through the sense function,
通过 sense 函数
and then prints out how long it took to run that.
然后输出运行它所需的时间
Then, we reset the clock.
然后 我们重置该时钟
We do 10,000 iterations on blur.
做 10,000 次模糊迭代
Print out how long it took.
输出所需的时间
10,000 iterations on this normalized function,
对这个规范化函数进行 10,000 次迭代
how long it took. Tests out move.
花了多长时间 测试出滚动函数的结果
So you can see we're going through each of these files,
所以你可以看到我们正在浏览每一个文件
where each of these files represents a function
其中每个文件都代表一个函数
and testing how long it's taking to run those.
并测试运行它们各自所需的时间
And your job is to go into all of these files and say,
而你的工作是打开这些文件 然后问问自己
"Hey, what's going on?
“ 嘿 怎么了？
Why is this so slow?
为什么这么慢？
What can we do to make it faster?"
我们能做些什么来加快速度？”
So, if you go back to the instructions file,
如果返回到之前的说明文件
like you've seen previously,
就像你以前见过的一样
we have given the terminal code to get everything running.
我们已经给出了终端代码 一切可以运行起来了
So, if I go change directory, andy_histogram_filter,
如果我去改变目录 andy_histogram_filter
hit enter, and now I'm in the histogram, andy_histogram_filter folder,
点击进入 现在我在直方图 andy_histogram_filter 文件夹中
I'm just going to copy and paste this because it's kind of long.
我们只需要复制并粘贴这个 因为它太长了
This is going to compile the code.
这将会编译代码
Hit enter, and so you'll see over here that it's created this
点击进入 所以你会在这里看到它创建了
a.out file and then the last command./a.out,
a.out 这个文件 然后是最后一个命令 ./a.out
and it runs the file.
它将运行该文件
So it says, "Number of iterations,
然后会出现 “ Number of iterations
10,000 duration milliseconds initialize beliefs, et cetera, et cetera."
10,000 duration milliseconds initialize beliefs 等等 ”
And it gives you how long it took to run each of these functions.
它会告诉你运行这些函数所花的时间
So, let's go back here to the workspace and
现在 让我们回到工作区
change to optimized code because this is where you're
打开 optimized_code
actually going to be writing your code and changing your files.
你会在这里编写代码并更新你的文件
So if you go and open initialize_beliefs,
所以如果你去打开 initialize_beliefs
for example, you'll see we've got
你会看到我们已经有了所有这些代码
all of this code for already working functioning histogram filter.
而且这些代码已经使直方图过滤器运行起来了
You don't need to actually do anything to get it to work,
实际上 你不需要做任何事情 就可以让它运行起来
but you'll see that there are places where you can optimize.
但你会发现有些地方你可以做一些优化
And what we've done is we've given some ideas
我们所做的是 我们已经提出了一些想法
for what you can do to make things faster like optimization.
比如 做些什么可以让它运行得更快 如优化
Which of these variables are necessary optimization,
哪些变量是必要的优化
reserve space in memory for vectors?
是否要在内存中为矢量预留空间？
So, for example, this is just kind of a hint
这只是举个例子 只是一种暗示
that maybe you don't need all the variables,
暗示也许你不需要所有的变量
maybe there's some extra variables being created that take up memory,
也许还有一些额外的变量正在占用内存
are creating unnecessary read and writes and slowing down your program.
并且正在创建不必要的读取和写入 并让你的程序运行速度变慢
As you saw in the lessons, reserving space in memory for
正如你在课堂中看到的那样 在内存中为矢量预留空间
vectors can make things go faster as well.
也可以让程序运行得更快
So that's something to think about.
所以这是一个值得思考的问题
Here, there's a nested for loop which we talked about in the lesson as well,
我们在课堂上提到过一个 for 嵌套循环
the nested for loops can be pretty inefficient.
for 嵌套循环的效率可能非常低
So, maybe there's a way to do it with just one for loop
所以 也许有一种方法只用一个 for 循环就可以完成
or initializing things differently.
或以不同方式初始化事物
You're going to have to read through the code and figure out what could go better,
你必须要通读代码 并找出可以改进的地方
what could I do to make this run faster,
能做些什么来使运行速度加快
what could I do so that there are
能做些什么来让
fewer reads to memory and writes to memory that the CPU is asking for.
对内存的读取次数变少 并写入 CPU 要求的内存
So, there's actually a suggested order that you do in the project.
所以 实际上 在该项目中 我们会建议你一个顺序
If you go back to the overview section over here, you'll see order.
如果你回到这里的概览部分 你会看到该顺序
As a suggestion do,
作为一个建议
the project in the following order.
该项目将按以下顺序进行
I highly suggest doing it in this order,
我强烈建议你按照这个顺序来做
starting with zeros.cpp, initialize_beliefs,
从 zeros.cpp 开始 依次是 initialize_beliefs
sense, blur, normalized, move.
sense、 blur、 normalized、 move 函数
The reasoning behind this zeros.cpp, I think,
我认为 zeros.cpp 背后的推理
is one of the quickest optimizations and it doesn't have too much code.
是最快的优化之一 因为它没有太多的代码
So it's kind of a good warm up.
所以这是一个很好的热身
The other files, we've put in this order because this
其他文件 我们已按此顺序放置
is the order in which they get called in main.cpp and some of these functions.
因为它是它们在 main.cpp 其中一些函数中调用的顺序
Now, I use some of the other functions.
现在 我要使用其他的一些函数
So, as you say,
所以 如你所说
first start with zeros.cpp.
首先从 zeros.cpp 开始
I believe blur.cpp uses zeros.cpp.
我觉得 blur.cpp 要使用 zeros.cpp
So, if you've already optimize here,
所以 如果你已经在这里优化
your blur should already start to run faster.
你的 blur.cpp 应该已经运行得更快了
So let's go back to the project code for a second.
接下来 让我们回到项目代码片刻
So your main process for tackling all of this is going to be the following.
你解决所有这些问题的主要流程将会像下面这样
So, like I said, open zeros.cpp.
所以 就像我说的那样 打开 zeros.cpp
So, we have zeros.cpp which is going to
我们的这个 zeros.cpp 将会
initialize a 2D vector that has just a bunch of zeros in it.
初始化一个只包含很多零的二维矢量
We've said here, optimization reserved space in memory for vectors, newGrid,
我们在这里说过 优化矢量中的预留空间 newGrid
optimization nested for loop not
优化 for 嵌套循环是不需要的
needed because every row in the matrix is exactly the same.
因为矩阵中的每一行都完全相同
There might be other optimizations you think of as well that
你可能还会想到其他优化
might get your code to be even faster than the solution we've provided.
那些优化可能会让你的代码比我们提供的解决方案更快
So, this is not the be-all and end-all of optimization.
所以说 这并不是全部和最终的优化版本
These are just definitely ways that you can get the code to run faster.
这些只是确保你可以使代码运行更快的方法
So, I'm going to go here into the terminal and change my directory.
所以 我要在这里进入终端并更改我的目录
So, all I've done here is I've changed directory.
我在这里完成的是我改变了目录
Dot dot means go. Back up one step,
.. 意味着后退一步
which takes me back to workspace.
它将会把我带回工作区
And then I say, go and optimize code.
然后开始优化代码
So that's what this line is doing.
这就是这行代码的含义
So now I'm in the optimize code folder,
所以现在我在优化代码文件夹中
which you can see here on the left,
你可以在左边这里看到
and I have zeros.cpp open.
我已经把 zeros.cpp 文件夹打开了
I am going to compile the code.
将要进行代码编译
Let's look for that command here in the instructions.
让我们在说明中查找这个命令
Compile it, a.out to run it.
编译它 然后使用 a.out 来运行它
And this is the code in its natural state as given.
这就是所给出的自然状态下的代码
Now, zeros.cpp doesn't show up here because a lot of these functions use it.
现在 zeros.cpp 不会显示在这里 因为很多函数都在使用它
So it's not been tested separately.
所以它没有单独测试
By getting this to run faster,
通过让这个运行得更快
we'll get this to run faster as well.
我们也会让这个运行得更快
So what do we have here? We say,
那么 这里是什么呢？
optimisation reserve space in memory for vectors.
为矢量保留的优化内存空间
So, we have this height and width as our inputs,
所以 我们的输入是这样的高度和宽度
and we have newGrid and newRow.
这里是 newGrid 和 newRow
So I'm just saying here, newRow,
所以我只是在这里说
or let's start with newGrid.
让我们从 newRow 或 newGrid 开始
We have newGrid.reserve(height).
这里是 newGrid.reserve（height）
So we're saying newGrid.reserve is going to be
所以我们说 newGrid.reserve 将会是
a vector and it needs to have length of height.
一个矢量 它需要有高度的长度
And then, we're going to say, newRow.reserve(width).
然后是 newRow.reserve（width）
And so, if you remember back in the lesson,
所以 如果你还记得本课前面的内容
the reason why this might make your code run faster is
这可能会让你的代码运行更快的原因在于
because when you create a vector in C++,
当你用 C++ 创建一个矢量时
it reserves a certain amount of space,
它保留了一定的空间
but the program doesn't know in advance how much you're going to end up actually using.
但该程序并不能事先知道你将最终实际使用多少空间
So, if you go past the reserved amount of space that C++,
所以 如果你经过那个 C++ 的预留空间量
the compiler, automatically reserved for you,
编译器会自动为你保留
then the compiler needs to take the entire vector or find
然后编译器需要采用整个矢量
a new section of memory that's available and recopy the entire vector over,
或寻找一个新的可用内存部分 并将整个矢量重新复制过来
which is really inefficient.
这样确实效率很低
But if you know the length of your vector in advance
但是 如果你事先知道矢量的长度
and you reserve the amount of memory it's going to need,
并且保留了需要的内存量
well, then your compiler isn't going to have to do this whole recoping step.
那么 你的编译器就不需要做整个复制步骤
So what are we going to do? We just made this change.
那么我们要做什么呢？我们仅需做这个更改就可以了
And I'm thinking it's going to make the code run faster,
而且我认为这样会使代码运行更快
but do I really know? I can't know for sure.
但我真的知道吗？我无法确定
I need to test it out.
我需要测试它
That's a big part of optimization.
测试是优化的重要组成部分
You have ideas, and you have kind of your instincts and your feelings,
你有想法 而且有直觉和感觉
but instincts and feelings aren't always right.
但直觉和感觉并不总是正确的
So you need to test it out.
所以你需要测试一下
So I'm going to go back here.
所以现在 我回到这里
I'm going to use this command again to compile the code./a.out.
然后再次使用这个命令来编译 code./a.out
So, now let's compare what we had before and what we have now.
现在让我们来比较一下我们之前和现在的情况
This whole section is what we had before we made the change,
这整个部分就是我们在更改之前所做的
and this whole section is what we had after making the change.
而这整个部分就是我们在更改之后的版本
So, it looks like initialize_beliefs got a little bit faster,
看起来 initialize_beliefs 的速度稍微快一些
but it's not a lot faster. So, let's see.
但并不是非常快 所以 让我们看一看
Does initialize_beliefs use zeros.cpp?
initialize_beliefs 是否使用了 zeros.cpp？
It looks like it does not.
看起来没有使用
So, this difference is probably just because some randomness,
所以 这种差异可能只是因为一些随机性
every time you run your code there's going to be some sort of difference.
每次你运行你的代码都会有一些不同
But it looks like this normalize and
但看起来这是正常化的
this move function had a relatively significant change in time.
这个滚动函数在时间上有了较大的变化
So, I'm going to open move.
所以 我要打开 move 文件
And hey, look here, zeros.h.
看这里 zeros.h
That means that this is using the zeros function.
这意味着这是在使用零函数
And doing that really small change where we went into zeros.cpp,
在我们进入到 zeros.cpp 的时候 做了那个非常小的更改
and we reserved space in memory in advance seems like it got
并且我们预先在内存中预留了空间
us a good chunk of time off of our code.
似乎就是它让我们有很多时间去更改我们的代码
Let's just run the code again.
然后让我们再次运行代码
It's sticking around 40 milliseconds here at move.
在滚动函数 中 它将持续 40 毫秒左右
So, it looks like that helped.
所以 这看起来很有帮助
And how cool is that? I mean,
很厉害 是不是？我的意思是
you shaved off 20 milliseconds just by reserving the space in memory in advance.
你只需预先在内存中预留空间 即可缩短 20 毫秒
And so, when the move.cpp function ends up calling your zeros function,
所以 当 move.cpp 函数结束调用你的零函数时
this section of code is already running faster.
这部分代码已经运行得更快了
I don't want to give away everything because this is a really fun projects.
我不想做太多透露 因为这是一个非常有趣的项目
So I'll just going to kind of think about and just work and
所以我只想去思考一下 然后去动手尝试
see what gets things faster and what doesn't,
看看什么能让程序变得更快
and we've also provided the hints in the hints.md file if you go back to the workspace.
如果你返回工作区 你会看到 我们还在 hints.md 文件中为你提供了提示信息
But that's essentially the projects.
但这基本上就是整个项目
What you're going to do is go through each of
你要做的是看一看每个文件
these files and see what you can get to run faster.
思考一下 怎样做可以让程序运行得更快
And every time you make a change, test, test, test,
做了每次更改之后 你需要进行测试 测试 再测试
test because you might think something is going to make things faster,
因为你可能认为有些事情会让它变得更快
and it might be something that in the past has made something faster.
但这可能是在过去的情况
But every code is different.
但是每个代码都是不同的
Every machine is different.
每台机器也都不一样
So it's really, really important to test.
所以测试真的非常重要
If you don't test,
如果你没有测试
you might end up doing something that
你最终可能会让你的代码更慢
makes your code slower and then doing something else that makes it faster,
然后进行调整 才能变得更快
and you don't realize that your code is not as efficient as it could be.
而你并没有意识到你的代码并不总是那样高效
So, test, test, test.
所以 需要不断进行测试
The other thing I just want to mention here is that, so, blur, initialize,
我只想在这里提到的另一件事是 blur、 initialize
move, normalize, sense, and zeros,
move、 normalize、 sense 与 zeros
all of those files have places that you can optimize.
所有这些文件都有你可以优化的地方
So, print.cpp and main.cpp,
但是 print.cpp 和 main.cpp 这两个
you do not need to change.
你不需要进行更改
Main.cpp just runs your code and
Main.cpp 只是运行你的代码
prints out how long it's taking to do as I explained before.
和我之前的解释那样 输出所需的时间
Print.cpp, it's just included here if you want to use it to debug.
至于 Print.cpp 如果你想用它进行调试 它只是包含在这里
It has two functions in here.
它在这里有两个函数
One is print_vector_float, and one is print_vector_char.
一个是 print_vector_float 另一个是 print_vector_char
And the reason these two different functions are
它们之所以是两个不同的函数 原因在于
provided is in case you want to print out your 2D vectors.
说不定你需要输出你的 2D 矢量
We wrote the code for you so that you don't have to do it over again,
我们为你编写了代码 这样你就不必再重复一遍
but it'll be your responsibility to put in
但你有责任输入正确的标头
the header files correctly and put them in the right place.
并把它们放在正确的位置
And again, each of these files has ideas about what can be optimized,
此外 这些文件中的每一个文件都包含哪些地方可以优化的想法
and you might come up with other ideas as well.
你也可以想出其他的方法
If you go back to the workspace folder, actually,
如果返回到工作区文件夹
if you go back here on top,
实际上就是回到顶端
notice we've also provided this pages as projects solution.
你会看到 我们还为你提供了这个页面 作为项目解决方案
In the next section, we are providing a solution to the code optimization project.
在下一节课中 我们将为代码优化项目提供解决方案
Each file contains comments noting what
每个文件都包含注释内容
changes have been made to make the code run faster.
标注出了已做出更改的地方 这些更改可以使代码运行得更快
So, again, this is up to you.
所以 这也取决于你
We suggest that you do everything on your own without looking at
我们建议你先不要去看提供的解决方案 而是自己动手去做所有事情
the solution code until you're satisfied that your code is running quickly,
直到你对你的代码运行速度感到满意
but we have provided a solution.
但我们已提供了一个解决方案
Our solution is not necessarily the fastest,
我们的解决方案
fastest, fastest thing possible,
不一定是最快的
but it shows what we were able to come up with based on what was taught in the lesson.
但是它显示了根据本课所教授的内容 以及我们能够想出的优化方法
The other thing I want to mention again is going to the C++ Slack channel.
我想再次提到的另外一件事是 C++ Slack 板块
Once you have completed the project,
你完成了这个项目后
it's a lot of fun to post your results up there and compare your results with
将结果发布到那里 并把你的结果与其他学生进行比较
other students and even get suggestions for what can run faster.
关于如何才能运行得更快 你可能会获得新的建议
So, hopefully, after you've finish this project,
所以 希望在完成这个项目后
you'll have a real appreciation and understanding
你能真正理解
about how you can take this sort of inefficient code
如何在 andy_histogram_filter 中
here in andy_histogram_filter and go to
处理这种低效率的代码
optimized code here and make kind of small changes
如何去优化代码 并做一些小的更改
and get your code to run a lot faster just based on
根据你对 CPU 的了解以及它如何使用 RAM
your knowledge of what the CPU is doing and how it uses RAM.
让你的代码运行得更快